Hi everyone.
大家好。
I am Takumi, machine learning engineer at Google Advanced Solutions.
我是谷歌高级解决方案实验室的机器学习工程师Takumi。
Lab.
Currently a lot of people are talking about generative AI
目前很多人都在谈论生成式AI及其新进展，
and its new advancement,
and features.
But in this video series, our goal is not to create a state
但在这个视频系列中，我们的目标不是创建我们的
生成式AI的状态，也不是介绍谷歌云的新产品。
of our generative AIS, nor to introduce
Google Cloud new products.
Instead, we will explain what kind of technology has walking behind them.
相反，我们将解释这背后有哪些技术。
And especially in this video, I'm going to talk about
特别是在这个视频中，我将讨论如何实
际创建一个非常简单的生成模型，
how to actually create a very simple generative model,
image captioning model by using a technologies
使用诸如编码器解码器注意力机制和一点
Transformer的技术来创建图像说明文字模型。
like encoder decoder attention mechanism and a bit transformer.
If you're not very familiar with these concepts,
如果你对这些概念不是很熟悉，我建议
在此之前查看其他关于它们的视频。
I recommend checking other videos, talking about them
before this.
Okay.
好的，
So if you're ready, let's talk about image captioning tasks and data
那么如果你准备好了，让我们来谈谈图像说明文字任务和数据集，
set out first, we're going to use this kind of dataset.
首先，我们将使用这种类型的数据集。
As you can see, there are a lot of pairs of images and text data
如你所见，这里有很多图像和文本数据配对，我们的目标是构建
和训练一个模型，可以根据图像生成这种类型的说明文字。
and our goal is to build and train a model
that can generate these kind of takes captions based on images,
and we'll make it happen by building this kind of model.
我们将通过构建这种模型来实现这一目标。
As you can see, it is kind of encoder decoder model, but in this case, encode
如你所见，这是一种编码器解码器模型，但在这种情况下，
编码器和解码器处理不同类型的数据，即图像和文本。
and decoder handle different modality of data, which is image and text.
So we pass the images to encoder at first and it extract information
因此，我们首先将图像传递给编码器，它从
图像中提取信息并创建一些特征向量。
from the images and create some feature vectors.
And then the vectors are passed to the decoder
然后，将向量传递给解码器，逐个生成字来构建说明文字。
which actually build the captions by generating was one by one.
So this encoder part is easy.
这个编码器部分很简单。
You can use any kinds of image backbone like resonant
你可以使用任何类型的图像骨干网络，如
ResNet、EfficientNet或Vision Transformer。
efficient net or vision transformer.
What we want to do here is to extract features by using that kind of backbones.
我们想要做的是使用这些骨干网络来提取特征。
So code is very simple too, in terms of the code,
因此，代码也非常简单，在代码方面，我们将
在下一个视频中查看整个笔记本示例。
we're going to see the entire notebook example in the next video.
So here, let's just focus on some important
所以在这里，让我们只关注一些重要的行。
lines.
As you can see, we are using classical inception version of V2 here
如你所见，我们在这里使用了经典的
InceptionResNetV2，来自Carousel应用程
序。
from Carousel Applications.
But again, this can be any image backbones.
但是，这可以是任何图像骨干网络。
So the next part that the quarter is a bit complex.
接下来的部分有点复杂，让我们仔细看看。
So let's take a look very carefully.
So this is the entire architecture of the decoder.
这是解码器的整个架构。
It it gets was one by one
它逐个获取，并将编码器输出中的词和图
像信息进行组合，尝试预测下一个词。
and makes the information of wires and images
which is coming from the encoder output
and tried to predict the next wires.
So this decoder itself is in kind of iterative operation.
解码器本身是一种迭代操作。
So by calling it again and again or to regress fully,
通过反复调用或回归，最终可以生成六条说明文字。
we can eventually generate six captions.
There are so many
有很多这种解码器设计的变体，但在这里我们构建了类似
于Transformer的架构，尽管我们仍然使用RNN GRU。
variations for this decoder design, but here we build transformer
like architecture, although we still use are in RNN GUR.
So let's zoom into each component.
让我们放大每个组件。
The first embedding layer creates word embeddings,
第一个嵌入层创建了单词嵌入，这在其他视频
中已经讨论过了，我们将其传递给GUR层。
which was discussed in other videos
and we are passing it to GUR layer.
If you forgot what you are your guess.
如果你忘记了你猜的是什么。
It's a variation of recurrent neural network
这是一种循环神经网络的变体，或者你可以称之为
RNN，RNN接收输入并更新其内部状态并生成输出。
or you can call r in n
r n n takes inputs and updates
its internal states and generate output.
So by passing sequential data like text data, it keeps two sequential
所以通过传递序列数据，如文本数据，它可以保持序列依赖性。
These from previous inputs like previous was
这些来自以前的输入，比如之前的词，那个GRU的输出
进入了注意力层，它混合了文本和图像的信息。
that grow output goes to attention layer
which mixes the information of texts and image
in TensorFlow Keras, we can use
在TensorFlow Keras中，我们可以像使用其他层一样使用预定义的层。
predefined layers in the same way as other layers.
There are multiple implementations,
有多种实现，但是我们在这里简单地使
用了tf.keras.layers.Attention。
But if you want to use more transformer like architecture, you can know. So
但是，如果你想使用更像Transformer的架构，你可以了解tf.
keras.layers.MultiHeadAttention，它使用多个注意力头。
the pick up tf cross layers most attention
which uses multiple attention heads.
You can simply switch and use it in almost the same way.
你可以简单地切换并以几乎相同的方式使用它。
Inside our attention layer, it looks like this as you may
在我们的注意力层中，你可能已经在关于注
意力机制的另一个视频中看到了这个。
have already seen in another video about attention mechanism.
0 But the unique thing here is it pays
但这里独特的是，它通过处理文本数据关注图像特征，
这样，它可以通过混合两种信息来计算注意力分数。
by doing so, it can calculate attention
score by mixing both information.
Going back to code,
回到代码，你可以看到这个注意力层接受两
个输入，gru_ouput和encoder_output。
you can see this attention layer takes two inputs
Internally, GRU ouput is used as attention
在内部，GRU的输出用作注意力查询和键，编码器输出用作值。
query and key and encoder output as value.
The last components are add layer
最后的组件是Add层和LayerNormalization层。
and layer normalization layer
Add layer
Add层只是添加两个相同的移位向量。
Just add two same shift vectors.
As you can see here, the GRU ouput as passed to attention
如你所见，GRU的输出被传递给我们讨论过的注意力层以及直
接传递给这个Add层，这两个流最终在这个Add层中合并。
layer as we discussed and to this Add layer directly,
these two flows are eventually
marched in this Add layer.
is called skip connection, which has been a very popular
deep neural network design pattern since Resonant.
So it is also called residual connection.
因此，它也被称为残差连接（Residual Connection）。
This skip connection is very useful, especially when you want to design
这种跳跃连接非常有用，尤其是当你想设计一个
非常深的神经网络时，它还用于Transformer。
a very deep neural network and it is also
used in the transformer.
With this now we could build an entire decoder,
有了这个，我们现在可以构建一个完整的解码器，因此我们准备
使用说明文字数据集训练编码器解码器图像说明文字模型。
so we are ready to train the encoder decoder image
captioning model using the captioning dataset.
We will see how it works in the next video.
我们将在下一个视频中看到它是如何工作的。
But before moving on to the next one,
但在继续下一个之前，我想多解释一下关于推理阶
段的内容，在这个阶段我们实际上可以为图像生成
说明文字，因为这个过程可能看起来有点复杂。
I want to explain a bit more about inference phase
where we can actually generate captions for obviously images
because this process may look a bit complex
here.
We can see three steps and we're going to implement
在这里，我们可以看到三个步骤，我们将在
一个自定义推理函数中实现这些步骤，
these steps in a custom inference function,
and create a star token
in training phase.
TensorFlow Keras can automatically handle
TensorFlow Chorus可以自动处理每个序列的状态，
but in this inference phase, since we design our own custom function,
但在这个推理阶段，由于我们设计了自己的自定
义函数，我们需要明确地编写处理它的逻辑。
we need to write a logic to deal with it explicitly.
So at the beginning of each captioning
因此，在每个说明文字的开始，我们明确地用某个值初始化GRU状态，
we explicitly initialize the GRU state
with some value
and at the same time
同时记住我们的解码器是一个自回归函数。
remember our decoder is an auto regressive function.
But since we haven't get any wider prediction yet at the beginning
但是由于我们在推理开始时还没有得到任何预
测，所以我们从一个特殊的开始Token开始。
of the inference we start talking, which is a special token.
That means the beginning of a sentence
这意味着一个句子的开始，
number 2%
第二，将图像输入到编码器，并按照我们讨论的进行特征向量的提取，
input image to the encoder and instruct the feature vector as we discussed
and number three passed a vector
第三，将向量传递给这个时间解码器，在for循环中生成一个说
明文字的单词，直到它返回一个结束Token，或者达到最大说明
文字长度，这只是一个指定一些数字的超参数，比如264。
to this time decoder and generate a caption word in the for loop
specifying some number like 264.
And in this full loop we define all the procedures of caption
在这个完整的循环中，我们定义了所有说明文字通过反复调用解码器
生成的过程，结束Token也是一个特殊的Token，意味着序列的结束。
generation by calling the decoder also aggressively
and token is a
special token two, which means to end of the sequence.
So when our decoder generate this token,
因此，当我们的解码器生成这个Token时，我们可以完成这个完整的循
环，或者当说明文字的长度达到某个最大长度时，可以跳出循环。
we can finish this full loop
or you can go out of the loop when the lengths of the caption
rigid, some number max capsule lengths.
Let's take a look at the code one by one.
让我们逐一看一下代码。
In the first step we initialize
在第一步中，我们初始化了两个东西：GRU状态和起始Token。
n which says start tokens
as the first input word for the decoder
in the next video, but it basically is just tokenized awards to our token,
which is the standard text pre-processing technique.
In the next
在下一步中，我们预处理输入的图像，
并将其传递给我们训练的编码器。
step, we pre process to input image habit
and pass it to the encoder we train.
In terms of the image pre-processing,
在图像预处理方面，它首先读取并解码JPEG，然
后将其从任意分辨率调整为特定分辨率，
it reads in decode JPEG in the first line and resize it
from any arbitrarily resolutions
to specific resolution
and it changes to scale from 0
接着在第三行将比例从0到255更改为0到1，
and the last phase decoder for loop.
最后是解码器循环。
It is a bit complex.
这有点复杂。
So I will explain in the next video more in detail with the actual code.
因此，我将在下一个视频中更详细地解释实际代码。
But the main thing here is to call the decoder
但这里的主要内容是通过传递三个事物来调用解码器。
by passing the three things.
Decode inputs means decoder inputs,
解码输入意味着解码器输入，它应该有一
个在上一次迭代中预测的词Token。
And as we talked, if it is the first iteration, this would be the start token
正如我们所说，如果这是第一次迭代，那么这将是
开始Token，GRU状态是我们讨论过的当前状态。
of state
is the current of state we discussed.
And please note that the recorder of this output,
请注意记录器的这个输出，更新了GRU的状态。
the updated GRU state
and last but not least features.
最后但同样重要的是特征，
This is the image feature we extracted with the encoder.
这是我们用编码器提取的图像特征。
By passing them we can get the actual next var the prediction.
通过传递它们，我们可以得到实际的下一个变量预测。
This is a very simple text generation model from images,
这是一个非常简单的从图像生成文本的模型，
but this kind of iteration is very similar
但这种迭代在很大的语言生成模型中也非常相似，
even in very large language generation models
like Google Board,
就像Google Board， 他们基本上也是以这
种方式预测下一个词，以自回归的方式，
they basically predict the next Var, also rigorously in this way,
one by one based on some information and learned knowledge,
一个接一个地基于一些信息和学习到的知
识，这些知识都嵌入在大量的参数中。
which is embedded in the huge number of parameters.
and then we will check what kind of captions
然后我们将检查这个模型可以生成哪些说明文字。
this model can generate.
Thank you so much for watching and see you in the next video.
非常感谢你的观看，我们下一个视频见。